Guide to the Puebla Archives
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Criminal Cases, 1570-1904; Series II
  - Case against José Ciriaco, for injury to José Roman, 1850 (Box 20, Folder 458)
  - Investigation of the escape from prison of Timoteo Torrillo, Clemente Morales, and José de la Luz Osorio, 1850 (Box 20, Folder 459)
  - Case against Hipólito Torres, for theft of an ox, 1850 (Box 20, Folder 460)
  - Case against Francisco Pérez and accomplices, for theft, 1850 - 1852 (Box 20, Folder 461)
  - Case against Anastasio Luna, for theft of a mule, 1850 - 1853 (Box 20, Folder 462)
  - Investigation of the injures of Pedro Pascual, 1851 (Box 20, Folder 463)
  - Case against Juan José, for serious injury to Vicente Montalvo, 1851 (Box 20, Folder 464)
  - Case against Jesús Vara and accomplice, for assault, 1851 (Box 20, Folder 465)
  - Case against Rafael Morán, for murdering Manuel Estéban, 1851 - 1852 (Box 20, Folder 466)
  - Case against Sebastián Ramirez, for pickpocketing, 1851 - 1852 (Box 20, Folder 467)
  - Case against Ambrosio Montiél for murdering Antonio Beroerra, 1851 - 1853 (Box 20, Folder 468)
  - Case against Juan Sánchez, alias "Matasiete", for robbery, 1851 - 1855 (Box 20, Folder 469)
  - Investigation of injury to Monico Alvarez, 1852 (1899) (Box 20, Folder 470)
  - Investigation of injury to José Anatasio Balderas, 1852 (1899) (Box 20, Folder 471)
  - Case against Mariano Casares, for abduction, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 472)
  - Case against Miguél Casco, for theft of silver, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 473)
  - Investigation of the death of Mateo Eugenio, 1852 (1899) (Box 20, Folder 474)
  - Case against Antonio García, for injury to Mariano Fernández, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 475)
  - Case against José María Lima and Francisco Benavides, for perjury, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 476)
  - Case against Antonio Osorio, for injury to Julían Xale, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 477)
  - Case against Gerardo Santos, for injury to María Gregoria Hernández, his wife, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 478)
  - Case against Calito Simanca, for robbery, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 479)
  - Case against José Soledad, for injury to José Zenteno, 1852 (1899) (Box 20, Folder 480)
  - Case against Diego Mitre and his wife María de la Luz García, for her robbery of the house of Zenón Acevedo, 1853 (Box 21, Folder 481)
  - Investigation of injuries suffered by Cristóbal Salazar, 1853 (Box 21, Folder 482)
  - Case against Manuel González, for injury to Cresencio Vargas, 1854 (Box 21, Folder 483)
  - Luis Soriano vs. Juan de Dios Morales, judge, for abuses and injuries, 1854 - 1856 (Box 21, Folder 484)
  - Mariano Cao y Varela vs. the court of Puebla, concerning misplacement of gold, 1854 - 1865 (Box 21, Folder 485)
  - Case against Gregorio García and Mariano Hilario, for the theft of two bulls, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 486)
  - Case against Antonio Hernández, for theft of sheets, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 487)
  - Case against José María Hernández, for injury to Pascual de los Santos, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 488)
  - Case against Carmen Juárez, for injury to Epitacio Ramirez, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 489)
  - Investigation of the escape from prison of Gregorio Minero, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 490)
  - Case against Santiago Osorio and accomplices, for theft, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 491)
  - Case against Manuel Peregrina, concerning defendant Felipe de Jesús Izuma, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 492)
  - Case against Joséfa Pérez, for injury to María de la Luz Palacios, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 493)
  - Case against Bernardino Sánchez, for a fight with José María Mellado, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 494)
  - Case against José de Jesús Trejo and José María Huerta, for theft of two donkeys, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  - Case against Tomás Villanueva and María Encarnación, for incest, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 496)
  - Case against José Ybon Morante, for theft of two bulls, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 497)
  - Case against Miguél Barragan and accomplices, for stealing cattle, 1855 - 1856 (Box 21, Folder 498)
  - Case against Francisco Ortíz and accomplices, for injury to Guadalupe Pérez, 1855 - 1856 (Box 21, Folder 499)
  - Case against José Estevez, for injury to Florencio Ramirez, 1855 - 1858 (Box 21, Folder 500)
  - Case against Felipe Pulida, priest of Tepanco, for conspiracy against the Supreme Government, 1856 (1899) (Box 21, Folder 501)
  - Information given to the Secretary of Justice of the State Government concerning the Army Insurrection, 1859 January 10 (Box 21, Folder 502)
  - Case against Bernardino Juárez and Antonio Roldán, for injury to Trinidad Medel, 1857 (Box 21, Folder 503)
  - Case against José María Cortés, for murder of Vicente Bueno, 1857 - 1858 (1898) (Box 21, Folder 504)
  - Investigation of the death of three thieves, 1858 (Box 21, Folder 505)
  - Case against María de la Luz Tlexcalache and accomplice for injury to Juana Serrano, 1858 (Box 21, Folder 506)
  - Case against Diego de Jesús and accomplices, for injury to Clemente Castellano, 1858 - 1859 (Box 21, Folder 507)
  - Case against Felipe Jiménez and accomplices, for a conspiracy against the government, beginning 1858 Oct 9, 1858 - 1859 (Box 21, Folder 508)
  - Case against José Urbano and accomplices for assault, 1858 - 1859 (Box 21, Folder 509)
  - Case against Mariano Cordero, for theft of a sarape, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 510)
  - Case against Dolores Cortés and Marcos Moreno, for adultery, 1859 -1860 (Box 22, Folder 511)
  - Case against José María Cruz and the soldiers of his section, for sedition, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 512)
  - Case against Miguél Guillén, for conspiring with the enemy, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Investigation of the injury to Antonio Martínez by Pedro Mora, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 514)
  - Case against Micaela Salazar, for theft, 1859 (Box 22, Folder 515)
  - Case against José María Pérez, for assaulting Bartolo Vega, 1859 -1860 (Box 22, Folder 516)
  - Case against Manuel de la Trinidad, for robbery, 1859 - 1861 (Box 22, Folder 517)
  - Case against Pedro Apolinario and Hermenegildo Ibarra, for assault, 1859 - 1862 (Box 22, Folder 518)
  - Investigation of the death of Francisco de la Trinidad Tecua, 1861 (1899) (Box 22, Folder 519)
  - Pedro Zafría vs. Mariano Maldonado for injury and attempt to murder, 1861 - 1862 (Box 22, Folder 520)
  - Case against José Gabriel Ramirez and Joséfa Francisca for incest and for theft of jewels and weapons from the Ranch of los Huajes, 1863 - 1865 (Box 22, Folder 521)
  - Case against Isabel Olivares, for injury to Micaela León, 1864 (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Case against Feliciano Trujillo, for theft of cattle, 1865 (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Case against Pedro Baltázar Muñoz, denounced by his wife, 1865 - 1866 (Box 22, Folder 524)
  - Case against José María Fernández, horse thief, 1866 - 1869, (1900) (Box 22, Folder 525)
  - Case against Andrés Galindo and accomplices for theft, 1867 - 1879 (Box 22, Folder 526)
  - Investigation of Gregorio Rodríguez and others, for theft, 1867 - 1886 (Box 22, Folder 527)
  - Investigation of clash between officers and soldiers against the police with the result of several wounded, 1868 (1899) (Box 23, Folder 528)
  - Case against Sisto Méndez, for theft of a calf, 1869 (Box 23, Folder 529)
  - Case against Ignacio Méndez, for robbery, 1870 (Box 23, Folder 530)
  - Case against Andrés Galindo, for robbery (see also folder 533), 1870 - 1879 (Box 23, Folder 531)
  - Investigation of the robbery of Gabriela Alcalde de Tarve, 1872 (1898) (Box 23, Folder 532)
  - Action to arrest Andrés Galindo, for robbery (see also folder 531), 1875 - 1877 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Case against Antonio Ferreros, for injury to Maríana Caballero, 1878 (1899) (Box 23, Folder 534)
  - Case against Felipe Huerta, for injury to Dionicio Francisco Reyes, 1878 (1899) (Box 23, Folder 535)
  - Case against Antonio de P. Rodríguez, for injuries, 1904 (Box 23, Folder 536)
  - Case against several for sedition (in complete), Undated [before 1810] (Box 23, Folder 537)
  - Juana Carranza vs. Joséf Mariano Rozas, for injury, undated (Box 23, Folder 538)
  - Petition to the Governor by Antonio Flores that he be relieved of his prison sentence because of injury, undated (Box 23, Folder 539)
  - Petition to the Governor by José Ignacio Herrera and Manuel Acuna, to be released from prison, undated (Box 23, Folder 540)
  - Petition to the Governor Lázaro Tanstino and Augustín de la Cruz vs. Marías Muñoz, for injuries to themselves and to their father, undated (Box 23, Folder 541)
- Civil Cases, 1567-1878; Series III
  - Andrés Pérez vs. Pedro Hernández Asenzio, 1567 (Box 23, Folder 542)
  - Petition by Feliciano, concerning a horse, 1572 (Box 23, Folder 543)
  - Inquiry into the petition of Pedro del Toral and Pablo de la Cadena, concerning loans to the community of Indians of Cholula, 1572 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Pedro Pérez Cambrón vs. Antón Martyr, 1576 (Box 23, Folder 545)
  - Alonso de Arroyo vs. Juan Alonso, concerning horse, 1579 (Box 23, Folder 546)
  - Pedro Buzón vs. Jorge Gretín, concerning vinegar, 1580 (Box 23, Folder 547)
  - Pedro López de Fuentes vs. Francisco Méndez and others concerning the claim of the Co. of Jesús, 1580 (Box 23, Folder 548)
  - Request by Juan de Solís that Francisco Enríquez return his Indian, Miguél Vásquez, 1581 (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Lorenzo Figueroa and Judge of Probate vs. the Estate of the late Alonso de Soria, concerning a sum of money, 1583 (Box 23, Folder 550)
  - Claim of Antonio de Sotomayor vs. the Estate of Miguél de Peravia, 1583 (Box 23, Folder 551)
  - Order to bring up the treatment of some judicial decrees of Cholula, upon petition by Alonso de Sosa, 1586 (Box 23, Folder 552)
  - Balthazar de Castro vs. Francisco Trujillo, concerning payment of a debt, 1588 (Box 23, Folder 553)
  - Pedro Juárez vs. Antonio Rodríguez, concerning the payment of a debt, 1588 (Box 23, Folder 554)
  - Gerónimo Rodríguez vs. Joan de Pro, concerning a sum of money, 1588 (Box 23, Folder 555)
  - Orduña Fernández vs. Pero Alonso and Lorenzo de Gamez, 1594 (Box 23, Folder 556)
  - Juan de Cortázar Espadero vs. Andrés de Pantoja and Alonso Márquez, concerning a sum of money, 1595 (Box 23, Folder 557)
  - Gaspar González vs. Francisco de Valencia, "el Mozo", 1595 (Box 23, Folder 558)
  - Gerónimo Gutiérrez vs. Manuel Alvarez, 1595 (Box 23, Folder 559)
  - Teodora de Santoyo vs. Benito de Lara, 1595 (Box 23, Folder 560)
  - Diego de Sosa vs. Cristóbal de Aponte, 1595 (Box 23, Folder 561)
  - Martín Jiménez de Valejo vs. Juan Pérez de Morales, concerning a sum of money, 1595 (Box 23, Folder 562)
  - Petition by Manuel de Madrid y Luna concerning his case, 1600 (Box 24, Folder 563)
  - Will of Melchora de Solis, 1601 (Box 24, Folder 564)
  - Petition by Pedro de Anzures that he be dissolved of partnership in the business of Miguél García, his son-in-law, 1602 (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Division of the Estate of Miguél Hernández Salmoral among his sons, 1607 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - Will of Pedro Naranjo, 1608 (Box 24, Folder 567)
  - Heirs of Alonso Domínguez vs. Diego López Bueno, concerning payment of a debt, 1610 (Box 24, Folder 568)
  - Manuel Enríquez vs. Sebastián Fernández, concerning payment of a debt, 1614 (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Petition by Francisco Nicolás concerning the case against Miguél de Cavala, 1614 (Box 24, Folder 570)
  - María Méndez de Galvez vs. Juan de Aguilar, concerning payment of a sum of money, 1614 - 1615 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Melchor Alejo vs. Nicolás Carrillo, 1616 (Box 24, Folder 572)
  - Pedro Ortíz vs. Pedro Godines, concerning payment of a debt, 1617 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Juan de Ballesteros vs. Lorenzo de Dueñas, concerning a sum of money, 1619 (Box 24, Folder 574)
  - Will of López de Soliz, 1622 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - Title of a house, "Los Herreros," with deeds of sale, 1624 - 1813 (Box 24, Folder 576)
  - Cristóbal de la Carrera vs. Jerónimo de España, 1625 (Box 24, Folder 577)
  - Will of Juan Gonzáles Rico, Inventory of his Estate and division of it among his heirs, 1625 (Box 24, Folder 578)
  - Joana Briceño vs. Miguél de Mena Aluardo, for a sum of money, 1626 (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - Claim of Diego Tinoco, information as to how Juan Tinoco is a natural Indian, 1626 (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - Diego Hernández y Juan Hernández, Indians, vs. Miguél de Velasco, concerning payment for their personal services, 1627 (Box 24, Folder 581)
  - Will of Pedro Gonzáles, Inventory of his Estate and division of it among his heirs, 1631 (Box 24, Folder 582)
  - Judicial decrees in Memory of Joan López, Indian, who died in the hospital of San Bernardo, 1633 (Box 25, Folder 583)
  - Joan Carillo de Anzures vs. Francisco de Morales concerning payment of a debt in gold, 1637 (Box 25, Folder 584)
  - Pedro de Bonilla, merchant, vs. Antonio Fragoso, concerning a payment of a debt, 1637 (Box 25, Folder 585)
  - Meeting of Creditors of the Estate of Matheo Hernández Palacios, concerning money in gold, 1637 (Box 25, Folder 586)
  - Claim of Domingo Méndez vs. Antonio de Arteaga for a sum of money, 1637 (Box 25, Folder 587)
  - Meeting of Creditors of the Estate of Sebastián Díaz, for a sum of money, 1637 - 1644 (Box 25, Folder 588)
  - Alonso Díaz de Aguilar vs. Francisco Tinco, concerning payment of a debt, 1640 (Box 25, Folder 589)
  - Inventory of the Estate of the late Josépha Ruíz Sobrino, judgment of division of her estate, 1640 - 1673 (Box 26, Folder 590)
  - Inventory of the Estate of the late Miguél del Castillo, 1643 - 1663 (Box 26, Folder 591)
  - Domingo de la Edeja, merchant, vs. Marta Rodríguez, concerning 200 pesos, execution of the suit, 1642 - 1663 (Box 26, Folder 592)
  - Inventory and Records of division of the estate of Gaspar Hurtado, bachelor, among his sons and heirs, 1642 - 1665 (Box 26, Folder 593)
  - José de Loayza vs. María Corona, concerning the payment of a debt, 1642 - 1667 (Box 26, Folder 594)
  - Will and Inventory of the Estate of the late Diego de Vaena, 1642 - 1676 (Box 26, Folder 595)
  - Judicial decrees, concerning the lack of revenue of Marcos Gómez, merchant, 1642 - 1677 (Box 26, Folder 596)
  - Antonio Palomino, lawyer, vs. María Mauleon concerning gold pesos, 1642 - 1677 (Box 26, Folder 597)
  - Inventory of the Estate of Diego de Canaveral and records of division of estate amongst his heirs, 1642 - 1682 (Box 26, Folder 598)
  - Convent of St. Catarina de Siena vs. Lazaro Benítez and his estate; execution of the suit for the payment of a debt, 1642 - 1682 (Box 26, Folder 599)
  - María Leonaria vs. Sebastián Rodríguez, 1645 (Box 27, Folder 600)
  - Division of the Estate of the late Francisco Hernández and Anamaría de Almazán, his wife among their heirs, 1648 (Box 27, Folder 601)
  - Juana Cepillo de Lovara vs. Pedro Ruís Maldonado, concerning money in gold, 1651 (Box 27, Folder 602)
  - Record of Executorship of the Estate of the late Melchor de Bonilla, 1652 (Box 27, Folder 603)
  - Ana de Rivera Corrientes vs. Franco de Torres concerning payment of a debt, 1653 (Box 27, Folder 604)
  - Bernardo de Saenz Cabezón vs. Pedro de Cardenas concerning payment of a debt, 1654 - 1659 (Box 27, Folder 605)
  - Case of Francisco Gallo and Juan López, peddlers, for not manifesting their goods, 1654 - 1694 (Box 27, Folder 606)
  - Ana María Hizo vs. Juan Olinque, her husband, concerning his mistreating her, 1655 May 14 (Box 27, Folder 607)
  - Care of the Dowry of Isabel de Monte Alegre Ledesma, widow of Joséph de Villanueva, 1662 (Box 27, Folder 608)
  - Judicial decrees by the Mayor and citizens of San Pablo Guilla vs. Marina Ruíz, widow of Martín de Velasco, for damages caused by her cattle, 1666 - 1685 (Box 27, Folder 609)
  - Judgment concerning decision of the estate of Francisco Marquez, 1673 - 1693 (Box 27, Folder 610)
  - Captain Thomas López de Lagar vs. Juan ?, Indian, his servant, 1677 (Box 27, Folder 611)
  - Juan de Medina, acknowledgment of debt to María de los Angeles, 1682 (Box 27, Folder 612)
  - Case concerning the teachers Franco de Bonilla, Franco de Balderama and Antonio de la Parra, 1685 (Box 27, Folder 613)
  - Juan Bautista de Salaysses vs. Justo Cavallero, concerning payment of a debt, 1694 (Box 27, Folder 614)
  - Petition by María Ignacia del Solar concerning the estate of her late husband José Ignacio del Carrillo, 1696 (Box 28, Folder 615)
  - Inventory of partition of the Estate of the late Francisca Torre Mercado, 1697 - 1770 (Box 28, Folder 616)
  - Judgment concerning division of the Estate of the late Juan Tamayo among his heirs, 1699 - 1711 (Box 28, Folder 617)
  - Alonso de Ballarta Palma vs. the Estate of Manuel Margarita de Estrada Galindo, widow of Capt. Jerónimo de Salazar Méndez concerning 2,000 pesos, 1702 - 1713 (Box 28, Folder 618)
  - The Estate of the Alms of Sta-Bula vs. the Estate of Inés Lopes de Priezo, concerning 572 pesos, 1702 - 1715 (Box 28, Folder 619)
  - Francisco Cantonad and Miguél de la Guarda concerning the Estate of the late Micaela de la Guercia, his wife; inventory of, 1702 - 1723 (Box 28, Folder 620)
  - Will, inventory and preliminary decrees concerning division of the estate of Bartolomé Sainz de Rosas, among his wife and heirs, 1704 - 1709 (Box 28, Folder 621)
  - Dispatches made concerning petition of Pascual de Cuevas concerning a cattle site, La Colmena, under this jurisdiction, 1704 - 1715 (Box 28, Folder 622)
  - Dispatches concerning petition of Joséph and Diego de Escobar, Indian brothers, concerning a cattle site, Xicalanco, 1704 - 1715 (Box 28, Folder 623)
  - Dispatches concerning petition by the Indians of Santiago Actitlán, under the jurisdiction of Chicontepque, 1704 - 1715 (Box 28, Folder 624)
  - Juan Felix Pinto vs. Nicolás de Santander, free mulatto, concerning a sum of money, 1706 - 1715 (Box 28, Folder 625)
  - Diego Francisco del Bosque vs. Alonso Ballarte y Palma, 1706 - 1717 (Box 28, Folder 626)
  - The School of Sta. Domingo Martyr of the choirboys of the Cathedral Church vs. Juana de Zepeda Mastas and Andrés Martín, her bondsman, concerning 32 pesos of rent due to the school, 1708 - 1717 (Box 28, Folder 627)
  - Possession of the land and water of Atzentlán given to Magdelena García y Gonzáles in accordance with the governors of Yuntepec, 1709 - 1738 (Box 29, Folder 628)
  - Elvira Zambrand, widow vs. Alonso Cavallero concerning a sum of money, 1710 (Box 29, Folder 629)
  - Case concerning Antonio de los Reyes, 1710 - 1717 (Box 29, Folder 630)
  - Manuel de la Asención Zerezo, widow of Miguel de Ortega y Bonilla vs. Domingo de Mena, Sgt. of Pardos concerning 185 pesos, 1710 - 1717 (Box 29, Folder 631)
  - Dispatches made concerning the petition of Martîn de Nava, principal Indian, concerning the land of Coyotemanco, belonging to Juan Pedro y Lorenzo de Campos under this jurisdiction, 1711 - 1715 (Box 29, Folder 632)
  - Judicial decrees concerning the land of La Pastora, belonging to Antonia Gallardo Barragan, because of the dispatch of Severino de Lazcano, commissary of the judge of this kingdom, 1711 - 1716 (Box 29, Folder 633)
  - Judicial decrees concerning the hacienda of Chalahuerapan, belonging to Cristóbal de Galvez, 1711 - 1716 (Box 29, Folder 634)
  - Cessio Bonorum by Josépha de la Cruz Delgado, widow of Matheo de Astorga, of the some houses in the Plazula San Agustén as payment to her creditors, 1711 - 1748 (Box 29, Folder 635)
  - Proceedings concerning cattle land, called San Miguél el Limón, belonging to Diego de Frías, 1715 (Box 29, Folder 636)
  - The citizens of Sta. Catalina Nicontepeque vs. Antonio Baragán and Cristóbal de Galvez concerning their lands, 1715 - 1716 (Box 29, Folder 637)
  - Second book of judicial decrees concerning the division of and meeting of creditors of the estate of the late Capt. Antonio de Clexasa, 1716 - 1727 (Box 29, Folder 638)
  - Settlement of the hacienda Chalahuiyapa belonging to Cristóbal de Galvez, 1717 (Box 29, Folder 639)
  - Meetings of creditors to the hacienda La Visitación, 1720 - 1858 (Box 29, Folder 640)
  - Juana de Garayta conferring power on Miguél de Guevara, 1721 (Box 30, Folder 641)
  - Juan Pérez Gonzáles vs. Joséph del Puerto, concerning the rent of a barnyard, 1721 - 1739 (Box 30, Folder 642)
  - Iglesia Catedral de Puebla vs. Diego Carpentero concerning payment of a debt, 1722 - 1728 (Box 30, Folder 643)
  - Convent of the Santísima Trinidad vs. a labor ranch Tetlatlalco, belonging to Thome Landero concerning money owed, 1723 - 1726 (Box 30, Folder 644)
  - Miguél Marquez Camarillo vs. Manuel Miastas concerning a debt for rents, 1727 (Box 30, Folder 645)
  - Case against the mayor of San Juan de los Llanos for having ordered 200 whiplashes to be given to D. Nicolás de la Gasca, 1729 (Box 30, Folder 646)
  - Joséph Onetto vs. Nicolás de las Heras concerning payment of a sum, 1720 - 1739 (Box 30, Folder 647)
  - Petition by Cristóbal Rodríguez concerning a debt owed him by Vacinto Sánchez, 1731 (Box 30, Folder 648)
  - Antonio de Olivares Ayllon, attorney, vs. Lucas de Torres Bernal, 1731-1734 (Box 30, Folder 649)
  - Sale at a house belonging to Gerónimo Pérez de Salazar to María de Vena, 1732 (Box 30, Folder 650)
  - Inventory and estimate of the estate of Joséph de Zárate, 1735 - 1744 (Box 30, Folder 651)
  - Will of Miguél Casimiro Pérez de la Guardia, and division of his estate, 1735 - 1765 (Box 30, Folder 652)
  - Joséph Vásquez, trustee of the hospital of Our Lady of Guadalupe concerning bills of the hospital, 1737 (Box 30, Folder 653)
  - Nicolás Moreno de Monetin vs. Mathias de Sotomayor concerning payment of a debt, 1731 (Box 30, Folder 654)
  - Diego de Palafor, priest vs. Antonio Xavier Ruíz, 1739 (Box 30, Folder 655)
  - Manuel Freire Ponceca vs. Franco de Torres concerning payment of a debt, 1739 (Box 30, Folder 656)
  - Franco Xavier de Vega vs. Miguél de Priego concerning debt owed in the settlement of a sale, 1739 (Box 30, Folder 657)
  - Antonio de Olivares Ayllon, attorney, vs. Gabriel de Escalona Murillo y Vellarde concerning payment of a sum, 1739 - 1757 (Box 30, Folder 658)
  - Petition by Gregorio Blancas Valenzuela that his wife be returned to him, 1740 (Box 31, Folder 659)
  - Decrees formed at creditors meetings concerning the Estate of the late Manuel Gómez Díaz, 1740 - 1813 (Box 31, Folder 660)
  - Francisco Pérez de la Raya vs. Juan Xaso de la Moto Osorio y Portugal concerning payment of a debt, 1741 (Box 31, Folder 661)
  - Petition by Diego Joséph de Campos that he be released from prison, 1744 (Box 31, Folder 662)
  - Sale of land. Marta de los Dolores de los Reyes Antonio Mastas, 1745 (Box 31, Folder 663)
  - Carrying out of the will of the late Rosia del Castillo, 1753 (Box 31, Folder 664)
  - Termination of the case against Fabian Gonzáles Calderón in accordance with two new decrees, 1753 (Box 31, Folder 665)
  - Joséph de Esquivel Arias de San Pedro vs. Ignacio Bernavides concerning a sum of money, 1754 (Box 31, Folder 666)
  - Inventory and estimate of the Estate of Maríana de la Riva y Estrada, 1754 - 1759 (Box 31, Folder 667)
  - Inventory and estimate of the Estate of the late Nicolás González, 1754 - 1765 (Box 31, Folder 668)
  - The convents of Sta. Rosa and San Jerónimo vs. Francisco Gómez for clandestine sugarmaking, 1754 - 1809 (Box 31, Folder 669)
  - Marion Alberto de Bertodano vs. Tomás Rodríguez de Varsas concerning payment of a debt, 1755 (Box 31, Folder 670)
  - Francisco Xavier Pérez concerning payment of debts, 1755 - 1756 (Box 31, Folder 671)
  - Dowry given to Euctaquia de Avedano by her husband Nicola Francisco Díaz, 1756 (Box 31, Folder 672)
  - Joséph Canallero vs. Antonio Romero concerning payment of a debt, 1756 (Box 31, Folder 673)
  - Bárbara Xaviera del Castillo vs. Manuel Romero concerning payment of a debt, 1756 (Box 31, Folder 674)
  - Juan Joséph Espinoza vs. Joséph Bergara concerning treatment of his house, 1757 (Box 32, Folder 675)
  - José Julián, Indian, vs. Franco Xavier de Esteban concerning payment for services, 1757 (Box 32, Folder 676)